atlasobscura.com 2019-12-10

# Privacy Policy - Atlas Obscura

#### Privacy Notice

_Last updated 5/18/2018_

The web site accessible through [www.atlasobscura.com](https://www.atlasobscura.com/) (the "Website") is owned, operated and distributed by Atlas Obscura Inc., a Delaware Corporation ("Atlas Obscura"). BY ACCESSING ANY PART OF THE WEBSITE, YOU ARE AGREEING TO THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS DESCRIBED BELOW (THE "PRIVACY POLICY") AND THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THE ATLAS OBSCURA TERMS OF USE (THE "TERMS OF USE"). IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO ANY OF THESE TERMS, YOU SHOULD NOT USE THE ATLAS OBSCURA WEBSITE. This Privacy Policy applies to all users, including both users who are simply viewing the Website and users who are also contributors of content, information, and other materials or services on the Website. Please note that any User Submission (as defined in the Terms of Use) becomes published content and is not considered personally identifiable information subject to this Privacy Policy.  
Atlas Obscura may, at its sole discretion, modify this Privacy Policy at any time. By accessing the Website at any time after such modifications, you are agreeing to such modifications.

**What Personally Identifiable Information Does Atlas Obscura Collect?**

Atlas Obscura collects the following types of personally identifiable information:

• _User Provided Information_ : You may affirmatively provide Atlas Obscura with certain personally identifiable information (such as your name and email address) when participating in various activities on the Website. 

• _Information Collected by "Cookies"_ : When you visit the Website, Atlas Obscura may send one or more "cookies" to your computer. A "cookie" is a small line of text that is stored with your Web browser, which Atlas Obscura uses to help provide better service to you. Your browser has options to accept, reject or provide you with notice when a cookie is sent. Atlas Obscura may use cookies for many purposes, including (without limitation) to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit the Website, and to deliver content (which may include third party advertisements) specific to your interests. 

• _Log File Information_ : Atlas Obscura's servers automatically record certain information that your web browser sends whenever you visit the Website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, browser language, referring / exit pages and URLs, platform type, number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular pages, the date and time of your request, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. 

• _Information Collected by "Clear GIFs"_ : Atlas Obscura may employ "clear GIFs" (a.k.a. Web Beacons), which are used to track the online usage patterns anonymously (i.e., in a non-personally-identifiable manner). In addition, Atlas Obscura may also use clear GIFs in HTML-based emails sent to users to track which emails are opened by recipients. 

**How Does Atlas Obscura Use Personally Identifiable Information?**

Any personal information that you voluntarily disclose online (on discussion boards, in messages and chat areas, within your public profile page, through a User Submission, etc.) becomes publicly available and can be collected and used by others. Your account name (not your email address) is displayed to other Users when you make a User Submission, and other users can contact you through messages and comments. 

If you have not opted out from receiving emails from Atlas Obscura, it may use your email address or other personally identifiable information to send commercial or marketing messages. Atlas Obscura also may use your email address for non-marketing or administrative purposes (such as notifying you of major Website changes or for customer service purposes). You cannot opt out of receiving emails for non-marketing or administrative purposes. 

Atlas Obscura uses aggregated information (such as anonymous user usage data, cookies, IP addresses, browser type, clickstream data, etc.) to improve the quality and design of the Website and to create new features, promotions, functionality, and services by storing, tracking, and analyzing user preferences and trends. In addition, Atlas Obscura may use "cookies" clear gifs and log file information to deliver content (which may include third party advertisements) specific to your interests, and remember information so that you will not have to re-enter it each time you visit the Website. 

We'll retain your personal information for as long as necessary to provide you with our services. You can ask for your personal information to be deleted at any time or ask for us to send you or a 3rd party your personal information by contacting us [via this form.](https://www.atlasobscura.com/contact_form) Please note that there may be latency in deleting your personal information from our servers and backup storage, and we may retain your personal information in order to comply with the law, protect our rights, resolve disputes or enforce our agreements.

**Will Atlas Obscura Share Personally Identifiable Information with Others?**

Atlas Obscura will not share your personally identifiable information (such as name or email address) with other, third-party companies for their commercial or marketing use without your consent or except as part of a specific program or feature for which you have the ability to opt-in or opt-out.

Atlas Obscura may provide personally identifiable information to employees, consultants, affiliates or other businesses or persons for the purpose of processing such information on its behalf. In such circumstances, Atlas Obscura requires that these parties agree to protect the confidentiality of such information and to comply in all respects with this Privacy Policy. If you wish to be exempt from this processing, you may request via [via this form](https://www.atlasobscura.com/contact_form) that we delete your account.

Atlas Obscura may share non-personally-identifiable information (such as anonymous User usage data, referring / exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) with interested third-parties to assist them in understanding the usage patterns for certain content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality on the Website and to serve interest-based ads on both the Website and trusted partner applications.

In addition, Atlas Obscura may release personally identifiable information: (i) to the extent it has a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with any applicable law, enforce any provision of the Terms of Use, protect itself against any liability, defend itself against any claims, protect the rights, property and personal safety of any user or protect the public welfare; or (ii) to respond to a court order, subpoena, or search warrant. 

**Third-party Advertisers**

Atlas Obscura may allow other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to serve advertisements within the Website. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send, directly to your browser, the advertisements and links that appear on the Website. They automatically receive your IP address when this happens. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize the advertising content you see. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers or ad networks for more information on their practices and for instructions on how to opt-out of certain practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to them, and Atlas Obscura cannot control their activities. 

We may use data from Google’s Interest-based advertising or 3rd-party audience data (such as age, gender and interests) with Google Analytics. You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads via [Google Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads), or opt out of general interested-based advertising via the [NAI Consumer Opt Out](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1). You may also be interested in the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). 

**Is My Information Secure?**

Atlas Obscura's application databases and related backups are encrypted-at-rest. Transmission of data between application servers, databases, and other services is over secure connections, and users may only connect with our web services using HTTPS. To prevent unauthorized access, our internal databases and application servers require two-factor authentication for all administrators. We employ web application firewalls, attack-detection, and similar services to prevent the authorized access of our public-facing services. Applications and underlying systems are monitored for security vulnerabilities and patched in a timely fashion when threats are discovered.

Atlas Obscura has implemented security measures to protect personally identifiable information collected on the Website against loss, misuse or alteration. In addition, your account information is protected by a password for your privacy and security. It is important that you protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer by logging off once you have finished using a shared computer. Moreover, despite the precautions described above, Atlas Obscura cannot and does not guarantee that the individual user information you have transmitted will not be intercepted by others and/or decrypted or accidentally disclosed, and it accepts no liability for any unintentional disclosure. 

**In the Event of Merger, Sale, or Bankruptcy**

In the event that Atlas Obscura is acquired by or merged with a third party entity, it reserves the right to transfer or assign the information it has collected from users as part of such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. In the unlikely event of Atlas Obscura's bankruptcy, insolvency, reorganization, receivership, or assignment for the benefit of creditors, or the application of laws or equitable principles affecting creditors' rights generally, Atlas Obscura may not be able to control how your personal information is treated, transferred, or used.

**Children's Privacy**

You must be 18 years and older to register to use the Website. As a result, Atlas Obscura does not collect information about children.

**Special Note to International Users**

The Website is hosted in the United States and is intended for and directed to users in the United States. If you are accessing the Website from the European Union, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure, that differ from United States laws, please be advised that through your continued use of the Website, which is governed by U.S. law, this Privacy Policy, and our Terms of Use, you are transferring your personal information to the United States and you consent to that transfer.

**California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits users of the Website who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please detail your request with [this form](https://www.atlasobscura.com/contact_form) or write us at:

Atlas Obscura Privacy Rights  
61 Greenpoint Ave #622  
Brooklyn, NY 11222
